Guide to the Allan Nevins Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: 1982 Gift
  - 1. Two AN letters (2) to Roland Baines written while abroad, 1912 -- 2. xerox of letter to AN from Ashley Thorndike, September 1, 1913, inviting AN to accept an instructorship in English Department, Columbia. -- 3. Cablegrams (5) sent by AN from England, 1940 (while he was Harmsworth professor at Oxford). -- 4. ANs description of an evening with Vishinsky, undated letter to Pete and Barbara Long. -- 5. AN letter to Pete and Barbara Long concerning work on volumes 8 and 9 of Ordeal. Undated but probably 1969. -- 6. Letters from Lillian Bean to AN (2) (included with other Bean letters) -- 7. AN letter to Norman Cousins concerning possible reviewing work after his stroke. (1969?) -- 8. Letter from Henry Commager to Anne Loftis, March, 1992. -- 9. Publication: ”The City of Mansoul“ an address of AN delivered on Founders Day, 1956, at Huntington Library. Publ. May, 1956. -- 10. Letters (25) to Mary Richardson Nevins: A. A.L. Rouse (2); B. Herbert Nicholson (1); C. Henry Commager (18); D. Lillian Bean (3); E. Louis Starr (2); F. E.M. flier (1); 11. Letter from Lillian Bean to Joseph G.E. Hopkins, editor, Scribners 1970; 12. A collection of photographs (41), 1930s to l971. (Box 205)
- Series V: Oversize Material
  - Two scrapbooks of newspaper clippings (Box 340)
  - Two scrapbooks of newspaper clippings -- Photo Album: "Dr. Allan Nevins, Personal Rep. of Pres. Kennedy to the Rizal Centennial Celebration..." (Box 340)
  - One scrapbook of newspaper clippings; memorabilia (Box 341)
  - Scrapbook (disbound) (Box 342)